# Carlos Daniel Jiménez M.

Colombia

🛮 (+57) 322-816-9956 | 🗷 danieljimenez88m@gmail.com | 🏕 www.danieljimemezm.com | 🖸 carlosjimenez88M | 🛅 djimenezm

# **Summary**\_

Experienced Senior Data Scientist, Machine Learning and Statistical Engineer with a demostrated history of working in Startups , and public institutions (Chile-Colombia-USA), I build Computational and Cognitive tools to make real world applications on Data Science, Machine Learning and Al. Skilled in Bayesian Data Analysis, Machine Learning applications, Statistical Modeling, Data Visualization, Lineal Algrebra, Markdown and LaTeX.

# **Work Experience**

Chiper Bogotá-Colombia

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST Nov 2019 - May 2020

- Build statistical models that allow knowing the needs of users
- Research the applications of Data Science.
- Developing Machine learning applications
- · Validated behavioral models on multiple datasets.
- Business Intelligence
- Implementing predictive maintenance tools using machine learning.

**Merlin Jobs** USA-Col

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST Aug. 2019 - Nov 2019

- · Developer and implementer Machine Learning models
- Research the applications of Data Science.
- Helping drive the strategic direction and priorities as solidify merlin as a top data science company in USA
- I Conducted customer interviews to understand their needs and help drive our data products strategy
- Develop models that translate unstructured client data into valuable insights

**Resolve Studio** Bogotá-Colombia

CHIEF DATA SCIENCE AND DATA ENGINEERING

Jan 2019- Aug 2019

- Lead Data Scientist and Machine Learning developer for autonomous attributions campaings with Deep Learnning and another technologies
- Developed Data Science models solutions for classification and Data Analysis
- · Lead Data Science Team for automate solutions and tasks throughout the company such as client sales prediction, demand forecast

**Big Bang Data** Bogotá - Medellín , Colombia

PRE SALES ENGINEER AND DATA SCIENTIST

Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2019

- · lead sales of products based on data and machine learning
- Developed Machine Learning models for: Marketing, Pricing, forecast, and Churn with differents clients
- Evaluated and Creator of work methodology

#### Secretaria de Educación Distrital

Bogotá - Colombia

DATA SCIENTIST Aug 2017 - Aug 2018

- Data Scientist on an advanced analytics team working in education projects and innovations in big data tools (RStudio and Hadoop)
- Build and own complex data pipelines using SQL and other data processing tools • I Created sampling model for Evaluated Educational Progress

## Superintendencia de Puertos y Transporte

2017

STATITICIAN AND QUANTITATIVE ANALYST • Created BI and tools that identify opportunities and some risk for projects

- · Worked with other departments to use new technologies to streamline Goverment policies and rules

· Developed a Mac and Windows python application for Policies evaluation software to measure employee productivity.

### **Puedo ser Consulting Group**

Jan 2017 - Sep 2017

• I developed of Statistics Models to: Clusters, Marketing Analytics and Forecast

• I created Statistics department

CHIEF STATISTICS

## **New Port Negocios Internacionales**

Bogotá - Colombia

March 2014 - Apr 2015

**NEW PORT INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS** 

- Researched on strategies to optimize pickup planning in warehouses
- Support Data Science initiatives across the company
- · Research the applications of AI in Marketing

JULY 7, 2020 DANIEL JIMÉNEZ · RÉSUMÉ **Invershop SAS** Bogotá - Col

Marc 2012- March 2014 MARKETING' CHIEF

- Researched on technologies to create scalable multi-tenant software Marketing
- Developing of intelligent reporting for supporting the Marketing management team
- Creation and development of Machine Learning algorithms for Marketing Strategies

#### ONU - Secretaria de Desarrollo Económico 'La Pintana'

Chile

ASSOCIATE FCONOMIST 2012

- · I Researched and analyze labor market conditions, national and MSA patterns, and past and future market trends and forecasts
- I created Psychology Test for Social development
- I Worked with media to customize Growth Destiny's data and insights for their stories/inquiries

# Academic Experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Bogotá, Col

PROFESSOR

Dic 2019 - Currently

- Manager and creator program's on Data Science and Big Data
- Data engineering teacher (with Python)
- · Digital Marketing teacher
- business architecture (Course designed for a company)

**Universidad Konrad Lorenz** Bogotá, Col

**PROFESSOR** Julio 2020 - Currently

- · Manager Data Science Area
- · Data Science Introduction teacher
- · Machine Learning teacher

Uniempresarial Bogotá, Col

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR March 2018 - Occasionally

- · Courses Creator on Data Sciene, BI, Computational Science and Econometrics for Business
- Academic Consultat on Metacognition
- Teacher subjects on university levels :Big Data, Computational Science, Statistics and Data Analysis

**Educación Futuro** Bogotá-Colombia

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR May 2015- Apr 2016

- · Teacher at the chair of Statistics and KPI's
- · Courses Creator on law of the unemployed: Innovation Diploma and Business Computing

**UniAsturias** Spain-México

**ECONOMICS PROFESSOR** • Full professor in following subjects: Microeconomics, Political Theory, Asian Economics, Economics History and Mathematical Economics

Education

Santo Tomás University Bogotá - Col

M.S. IN STATISTICS Jan 2018 - Currently

• focus in : Bayesian Statistics , EDA and Machine Learning Applied

**Michigan University** 

MASTER COURSE IN MACHINE LEARNING Apr. 2020 - Currently

Focus in: Data Science with applications on Emprirical Bayes

Santo Tomás University Bogotá - Col

Jan 2010 - Dec 2014 B.A IN ECONOMICS

· Focus in: Maths for Economics

## Tools\_

Programming: Python: +4, R: +9, Octave:+3, Matlab:+2

Data Science: Tidymodels, keras, Tenserflow, Scikit Learn, tidyverse, Spark, Bigquery, MySQL, Tidymetrics

**Development:** Docker, Git, Google Cloud Platform, Plumber, Flask.

Visualization: Shiny, looker, Power BI, Shiny metrics, Google Analytics

JULY 7, 2020 DANIEL JIMÉNEZ · RÉSUMÉ

## **Areas of Interest**

Applied Machine Learning, Natural Lenguage Processing, Statistical modelling, Bayesian data analysis, Web Scrapping, Forecasting and Deep Learning.

## Publications \_\_\_\_\_

## Inferencia estadística un enfoque moderno

www.danieljimenezm.com

FREE

2020

• Design of the theoretical framework of the application of statistical inference applied to data science

# **Extracurricular Activity**

danieljiemezm.com Colombia

BLOGGER Aug 2018 - currently

Blog on Applied Statistics, Data Analysis and Machine Learning with  ${\sf R}$ 

Nostradamusdata.com Col-Chile

TEACHER Jun-2019- currently

Special Professor on Data Science and BI